原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译     草草   苏小黛   暗夜骚王
翻译     苏葵   Fiona是小花
翻译     八秒   小酸奶   独乐乐众乐乐
校对     小酸奶
时间轴     Chance-coco   QueYian   西西查查
后期     8T
总监     小酸奶
《局外人》前情提要
从现在起  我们要假定
From now on, we have to assume that
它能通过克劳德看和听
whatever Claude sees and hears it sees and hears.
你问我我家人葬在哪
You asked me where my people are buried around here.
那个古老的熊洞  1947年后就被封住了
The old Bear Cave. It's been sealed since 1947.
他在那里面  我们找到他了
He's in there. We found him.
我们几小时后就回来了
We're gonna be back in a couple of hours.
这不对  不告诉他到底发生了什么
It's not right. Not telling them that that thing's out there.
如果它无法受控呢
What if it doesn't cotton to being contained?
那我们就在它杀死我们之前杀了它
Then we kill it before it can kill us.
如果它永生不灭呢
What if it can't be killed?
你知道你刚刚做了什么吗
Do you know what you just did?
我当然知道
I know what I just did.
我让你保住了小命
I gave you the heads up of your life.
他在我的脑子里  西里
He's in my head, Seale.
所以你刚刚告诉了这个玩意
So, you just told that thing
所有人都冲他去了
that all of those people are coming for it.
好嘞
There you go!
-天啊  -该死
- Jesus Christ! - Fuck!
我们得离开这里
We gotta get outta here.
-去哪  -我不知道  但我们得离开这里
- And go where? - I don't know. Just to get the fuck outta here.
枪手是谁
Who's the shooter?
杰克  我们可以谈谈
Jack! We can talk about this!
混蛋
Motherf--!
不不  别
No, no, no. Come on, come on!
-该死  -拿着
- Ah! Goddammit! - Take this! Take this!
混蛋
Motherfucker!
那是霍伊吗
Is that fucking Howie?
对  来吧
Oh, yeah, get in there.
-天啊  -别停  走
- Jesus Christ! - Keep going! Keep going!
-那是佩里吗  -快走
- Is that Pelley? - Go! Go! Just go!
-走  -快走
- Go! - Get the fuck out!
-快走  -天啊
- Move! - Jesus Christ!
天啊
Oh, my god!
西里  你干什么
Hey, Seale, what the hell you doin', man?
混蛋
Motherfucker!
不  下去
Oh, no! Get off!
-走走  -快走
- Go! Go, go! - Go now! Go now!
西里  你干什么呢
Seale! Seale, whatcha doin', man?
快回来
Get back here!
西里  快回来
Hey Seale, get back here!
中
I got you.
好啊
Yeah!
该死
Shit!
混蛋
Fucker!
我看到你了
I see you!
该死
Oh shit!
混蛋  起来
Fucker! Get up! Get up! Up, up--
快起来  走走
Get up, up, up, up. We don't have-- Go! Go!
该死
Oh, shit.
Fuck!
我们快走
Let's get the fuck outta here!
该死  西里
Oh shit! Seale!
克劳德  别去  该死  别
Claude! Don't go out! Damn it! Don't!
西里
Seale!
该死
Fuck!
混蛋
Motherfucker!
天啊
Oh, God, man.
打中要害了  该死
They got him good, man. Oh shit!
该死  该死
Fuck! Oh! Oh shit!
天啊
Oh, man.
中枪好疼  好疼
Fucking hurts to be shot, man. Fucking hurts.
是啊  他用的子弹
Yeah. With the slugs he's using,
你胳膊没被打爆不错了
you're lucky you didn't get your arm taken off.
-中枪好疼  -知道吗
- Hurts to get shot. - You know what...
如果我们能有信号
If we could just get some fucking bars!
想都别想
Don't even think about it.
诺曼底登陆日
Hey, when the GIs were getting chewed up
盟军遭遇火力时  上面怎么说的
on the beaches on D-Day, you know what they're told?
不前进就必死
Ad-- Advance or die.
-什么的  -太对了
- Or something like that. - That's fucking right.
你左手能打吗
Can you fire lefty?
可以  我也只能靠左手了
Yeah, that's about all I can do.
-拿着  拿着  -不不不
- Take this! Take this! - No! No! No, no, no!
安迪
Andy!
他要干什么
What the hell is he doing?
我他妈不...我觉得他要去找信号
I don't fucking kn-- I think he's going to get reception.
天  你就不能好好待在自己的位置上吗
Ah, Jesus, man. Why couldn't you stay where you are?
妈了个...
Son of a...
天
Jesus!
该死
Fuck!
快走  安迪  快
Go, Andy! Go!
-一  二  碰  -操
- One... two... boom! - Fuck!
快走
Just go!
妈的
Shit!
走啊
Go!
加油  安迪
Go! Go, Andy!
加油加油
Go, go, go!
发生什么了
What happened?
安迪  不
Andy! No!
不  不要
No, no!
不不不  豪丽  不  快回去
No! No, no, no! Holly, no! No, go back!
-我去接他  我去  你走  -不
- I'll get him. I'll get him. Go! - No!
回去
Go back!
天助我也
Mother nature!
豪丽
Holly!
豪丽  快回来
Holly! Holly, get back here!
该死
Fuck!
她他妈的在干什么
What the fuck is she doing?
豪丽  快回来
Holly, get back here!
豪丽
Holly!
快回来
Get back here!
你下地狱吧
Damn you to hell!
他一定会的
Oh, he definitely will.
操
Fuck!
去你妈的
Fuck you!
不会再听你的了
No more.
来咬我吧  混蛋
Come at me, motherfucker.
豪丽
Holly!
该死
Fuck.
来啊  过来
Come on, come on.
杰克完蛋了
Jack's done.
让萨布洛省省他的弹药
Tell Sablo to save his ammunition,
让他别打了  我...
and tell him to stop shooting. It's...
我的头都快被震裂了
It's splitting my head in two.
是时候了
It's time.
局外人
第一季第十集[本季终]
你自己在这里能行吗
You're gonna be all right out here by yourself?
我没事  你俩小心
I'll be fine. You be careful.
拉夫
Ralph!
把枪放下  杰克
Put it down, Jack.
杰克  快放下  伙计
Jack, just put it down, man.
它在那里面
It's in there.
灭了它
Kill it.
不
No!
小心
Watch out.
你没事吧
You okay?
没  没事
Yeah... Yeah, yes.
还是小心点
Uh, better be careful.
你看
Look.
他可以被杀死
He can be killed.
-怎么杀死他  -他害怕跌落
- How's that? - He's scared of falling.
就像我们
Like us.
他在进食
He's feeding.
来自地狱的面包屑
Breadcrumbs from hell.
熊洞
停下
Stop.
他原本陷入了疯狂
He was in a frenzy.
-豪丽  -怎么了
- Holly. - Hmm?
你看
Look.
一切始于这里
This is where it happened.
他们的名字都在这
They're all in there.
它肯定一直在疯狂地找他们
Must have been going crazy trying to get to them.
-豪丽  -怎么了
- Holly. - Hmm?
看见了吗
See it?
光
The light?
进来时小心脚下
Watch your step coming in.
地面很滑
It's very slippery.
不想滑倒时要扶什么  就靠墙走
Stay close to the walls in case you need to grab onto something.
你们好不容易来这里  可不想回去吧
You haven't come all this way just to turn back now, have you?
你好  警长
Well, howdy there, sheriff.
你肯定就是那位美丽的豪丽小姐
And you must be the lovely Miss Holly.
克劳德不知道你姓什么
Claude doesn't know your last name,
但他一直想着你
but he thinks about you all the time.
我姓吉布尼
It's Gibney.
豪丽·吉布尼
Holly Gibney.
我陷入这种处境
It's you I have to thank
还得谢谢你  不是吗
for this situation I find myself in, ain't it?
我想知道是什么让你这么
I wanna know what made it so easy for you
轻易地相信我的存在
to believe in me,
她又是如何设法说服
and how on earth did she manage
你这样的牛仔的  警长
to convince a cowpoke like you, sheriff.
你是什么
What are you?
-你叫什么  -知道吗
- What is your name? - Oh... you know.
你来自哪里
Where did you come from?
-我不记得了  -你的本来面目是什么
- I don't remember. - What is your nature?
我们是不是不太擅长回答彼此的问题
We're not very good answering each other's questions, are we?
-你们还有更多吗  -为什么这么问
- Are there more of you? - Why?
你之前见过我这样的吗
Have you seen someone like me before?
还有其他的睡仙吗
Are there others?
因为我也曾经觉得...
'Cause there have been times when I...
-有更多的...  -闭嘴
- sense there could be more-- - Shut up.
你不是想真的开枪吧  警长
You really gon' pull that trigger, sheriff?
如果你不怕死的话
Well, you go ahead and do it...
可以开枪试试
if you don't mind dying.
真的克劳德·博尔顿会站起来吗
Will the real Claude Bolton please stand up?
-看见没  -退后
- You see? - Step back!
别喊了
Stop yelling.
他们在这  那些死人
They're here, you know. The dead.
营救的人都救不了自己
The rescuers that couldn't even rescue themselves.
但你找不到他们  对吧
But... you couldn't get to them, could you?
那无所谓了  我能感知他们的存在
Well, it don't matter. I still feel their presence.
尤其是四个博尔顿家的  他们散发着光芒
Especially the four Boltons. They give off such a glow.
光芒
Glow?
他们是我慢慢成为的血液
They're the blood that I'm becoming.
这感觉
It feels like...
感觉有东西进入了我
like I'm being entered.
无论那是什么  都充满了我全身
And what enters me, fills me.
你根本不知道那种感觉
You have no idea what it feels like to have
浑身充满各种情感
all of that emotion inside of me.
为什么选孩子
Why children?
别再问问题了
Stop asking him questions!
我进食是为了生存  和你一样
I eat to survive, just like you.
-闭嘴  -为什么选孩子
- Shut up. - Why children?
因为他们的味道更甜美
'Cause they taste the sweetest.
-禽兽  -站住
- Motherfucker! - Stop!
他有毒
He's poison.
我不能让你们离开
I can't let you leave.
你知道  对吧
You know that, right?
不
No.
是我们不能让你离开
We're the ones who can't let you leave.
杰克留了一个我们的人在外面
Jack left one of us out there.
他知道我们在里面  他也知道你是什么
He knows we're in here and he knows what you are.
他会派增援
He'll send more.
这样
I see.
但我得进食
But I need to eat.
克劳德
Claude.
把枪放下
Put the gun down.
别开枪
Don't shoot.
别开枪  如果你开枪
Don't shoot. If you shoot,
整个地方都会塌
the whole chamber will fall on our heads.
克劳德
Hey, Claude.
把手指从扳机上移开  好吗
Just take your finger off the trigger, okay?
克劳德  就...
Claude, just...
看着我们
Just look at us.
就这样
That's it.
把枪放下
Now-- Now put the gun down.
我的天
Oh, my God.
开始坍塌了
It's collapsing.
逃  快逃  豪丽
Move! Now! Now! Holly!
克劳德
Claude!
豪丽
Holly!
护住脑袋  缩进衣服
Cover your head! Tuck your head!
这边
Over here.
-我动不了  -等等  见鬼
- I can't move. - Hold on-- Oh, shit.
好吧
Okay.
准备好了吗
Ready?
-三  二  一  -好了
- Three, two, one. Yeah. - Okay.
好了吗
You got it?
天哪
Oh, man.
-你还好吗  -嗯  死不了
- You okay? - Yeah, I'll live.
说了让你别开枪
Told you not to shoot.
好了  我们马上回来  抓紧
Okay. We'll be back in a moment, okay? Hold tight.
好的
All right.
该死
Ah, fuck.
你有刀之类的东西吗
Do you have some kind of knife?
很好
Good.
豪丽  别管了  不用拔了
Yeah, Holly. Leave it. Leave it. Leave it.
如果我们说是这东西杀了
If we were ever to claim that this thing
弗兰基·皮特森  他们会以为是我们疯了
killed Frankie Peterson, they'll write us off as loons.
就无法证明泰瑞是清白的
Terry's name will never be cleared.
泰瑞是谁
Who's Terry?
我杀死他了吗
Did I kill him?
对  对
Yeah. Yeah.
好了  兄弟
Okay, buddy.
我们数到三一起  好吗
We do this on three, yeah?
-好的  三  二  一  -二  一
- Okay. Three, two, one. - Two, one.
该死
Ah, shit.
-小心碰头  -好的
- Watch your head. - All right.
该死
Ah, man.
怎么了
What's wrong?
-没事  我马上来  -好的
- Nothing, I'll catch up. - Okay.
现在看着你装死
Now look at you playing possum.
我怎么知道的吗
How I know?
你心脏左边是什么
What's left of your heart.
无论是什么  它还在跳动
Whatever it's called, it's still pumpin'.
而且你没流出什么东西
Otherwise, you got nothin' comin' out.
木屑
Sawdust.
我不知道你能不能被杀死
I didn't know whether or not you could be killed.
我曾觉得你像其他人一样可以  但
I thought you could be like anyone else, but...
我不再那么确定了
I'm not so sure anymore.
我知道  那把刀确实
I know that, uh, this knife's certainly...
没有达到预期的效果  依我看
isn't doing the trick. Here's how I see it.
你很虚弱  你变得越来越虚弱
You're weak. You're getting weaker.
你没法跑
You can't run.
你无处藏
You can't hide.
你不能捕猎
You can't hunt,
这意味着你无法喂饱自己
which means you can't feed and fill yourself.
我可以马上轻易地离开这里了
There's nothing stopping me from just walking outta here right now,
带回一大车的游客  就看着他们
come back with a bus load of tourists and just watch them
他妈的推推搡搡
fucking push each other out of the way,
不顾一切地试图找到最好的角度
desperate, trying to get the best angle of
看看你残破的臭脸
what's left of your fucking face.
然后轮到好奇的科学团体
And then comes the ever curious scientific community.
他们一定会对你很感兴趣
They're gonna be real interested in you.
刺探  调查  注射  提取
Poking, probing, injecting, extracting.
他们会在你身上做切片
They'll cut little pieces of you off,
带回实验室
take it back to the lab,
就一直他妈的一片  一片  一片切你的肉
Just keep fucking carving you and carving you and carving you
直到
until...
对  你不想那样  对吧
Yeah, you wouldn't want that, would ya?
如果没有人知道你的存在
And it would serve our purposes
那样
much better...
对我们来说更好
if no one ever knew that you ever existed.
所以
So...
你必须消失
you gotta go.
他
He, uh...
他是为了我才来的
He came here to be with me.
这是唯一的理由
That was the only reason.
豪丽  当地警方随时都会来
Holly, the locals could appear at any stage.
我们需要赶快讨论一下
We need to talk pretty fast.
统一一下我们的说辞
Get our story straight.
佐治亚州调查局萨布洛副队来电
Lieutenant Sablo from GBI.
-我是海耶斯  -海耶斯  我是萨布洛
- Hayes. - Hayes, it's Sablo.
我们在田纳西州的西塞尔镇
We're down here in Cecil, Tennessee.
在一停车场发生了枪战
There was a shootout in the parking lot.
礼品店外  亚力克·佩里死了
The gift shop, Alec Pelley's dead.
霍伊·所罗门和杰克·霍斯金也死了
Howie Saloman is dead. Jack Hoskins is dead.
他们死了
They're dead?
枪手是个警察  你们自己人
The shooter was a cop. One of your own.
但他不是自己作的案
But he didn't act alone.
事实上  他是被人强迫的
In fact, he was compelled to kill by someone else.
他还有同伙吗
Like... he had an accomplice?
杰克·霍斯金
不  我不是说霍斯金有同伙
No, I'm saying Hoskins was the accomplice.
我觉得杀害弗兰基·皮特森的真正凶手
The alpha who I believe killed Frankie Peterson
仍未被我们抓到
is still out there.
在两天前  他企图
He attempted to grab another boy
抓住这里的另一个男孩
down here two nights ago.
他逃跑了
He got away,
但是有人拍到他了  我给你发链接
but we got him on video, so I'm gonna send you the link.
等等  等等  慢着
Wait, wait, wait. Hold on, just, uh...
这不是谁的错  好吗
It's nobody's fault, okay?
但我觉得你办公室做出的一些决定
But I believe certain decisions coming out of your office
需要重新推敲一下  你同意吗
need to be revisited. Wouldn't you agree?
西里·博尔顿接到了一通
So, Seale Bolton receives a phone call
匿名电话  他自称是我的同事
from an unknown individual who says he works with me.
此无名氏自称他知道
This individual claims to have knowledge of the whereabouts
很可能是弗兰基·皮特森凶案嫌疑人的下落
of a more likely suspect in the Frankie Peterson murder.
告诉我到底发生了什么  克劳德
You wanna tell me what happened, Claude?
-我跟你说过了  -我想再听一遍
- I already told you. -Well, I'd like to hear it again.
萨布洛警探和安德森警探
Detective Sablo and Anderson,
在诺基郡地检打算重审弗兰克·皮特森凶案时
they came to interview me when the Cherokee County DA
来找我进行询问
was considering reopening the Frank Peterson homicide.
为什么找你
Why you?
因为我说是他们逮捕的嫌疑人
Because I identified the man they arrested for it,
泰瑞·梅特兰  走进桃子瓣时
Terry Maitland, when he walked into the Peach Crease,
全身是血
covered in blood.
但你越仔细想
But the more you thought about it...
但我越仔细想
Well, the more I thought about it,
我越意识到我犯了错  那不是他
the more I-- I realized I made a mistake. It wasn't him.
那只是和他长得有些相似的人  只是这样
It was just someone who looked a little like him. That's all.
皮特森凶案的证人
Witnesses from the Peterson homicide.
把审问记录拿给我
I need the transcripts from the interviews.
这个打电话的人明确说让你去哪找他了吗
This caller, did he specifically tell you where to find him?
是的  山那边废弃的礼品店
Yeah, the abandoned souvenir shop on the side of that hill,
所以我们就过去调查
so we went to investigate.
-你们去了那边  -是的  我的怀疑是
- You went there? - Yeah. My assumption is that
他是为了干掉克劳德·博尔顿才去的
he's there to take out Claude Bolton,
他觉得克劳德是个威胁
who he perceives as a threat.
你说的他是杰克·霍斯金吗
Him being Jack Hoskins.
他是你的队伍里的警探
The detective from your squad
因绑架  谋杀未遂而失踪
who's been in the wind for kidnapping, attempted murder.
同一个人
The same.
所以我把这通电话理解为
Yeah, so, I, uh... interpreted the phone call
一个陷阱
as being made to set up an ambush.
老实说  我以为整件事
Frankly, I thought the whole thing
会是一个骗局
was gonna turn out to be bullshit.
我错了
Was wrong.
他们会扣留我弟弟的遗体多久
How long they gonna keep my brother's body for?
希望不会太久
Hopefully not for too long.
不太久是多久
Well, how long is not too long?
克劳德  跟我说说电话的事
Claude, tell me about the phone call.
三月三日到七日
March 3rd through the 7th,
梅特兰最后一次去探望他父亲...
Maitland's last visit to see his father, um...
我在调查的过程中  遇见了卡卡瓦奇先生
On my investigation, I encountered Mr. Katcavage,
...前代顿警察局探员  他这些年来
uh... former Dayton PD detective who had worked dozens
经手了十几起凶杀案  我发现他...
of homicides over the years. I found him...
我发现他能力很强
I found him, uh, highly competent,
所以我推荐我的雇主...
so I recommended that my employer...
雇请他加入团队
hire him as part of the team.
嗨  亲爱的  是我
Hey, darlin', it's me.
珍妮  如果我们要结束这件事
So if we're gonna pull this off, Jeannie,
我需要你做点事
there's something I need you to do.
谢谢  谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
不管你接受还是拒绝那东西的存在
Whether you accept or reject the reality of that thing,
现在不重要  重要的是...
it's not important right now. What is important...
当他们问你
is that when they ask you,
他们肯定会问你
and they will definitely ask you
和豪丽·吉布尼见面的事
about that meeting with Holly Gibney,
请不要提到变形
please don't mention anything about shape shifters
睡仙  或其它听起来超自然的内容
or El Cucos or anything that might sound supernatural.
好吗
Okay?
否则...
Otherwise...
可以
I can do that.
梅特兰夫人  我今天过来告诉你
What I've come to tell you today, Mrs. Maitland...
弗兰基·皮特森被害案件
is that there have been certain developments
已经取得一定进展
in the Frankie Peterson homicide case.
已经展开一些新的调查途径
Some new avenues of inquiry have opened.
我们正在重新启动这件案子
We're reopening the case.
那你们所谓一锤定音的法医鉴定呢
What about your slam dunk forensics?
我们重新检验了犯罪现场
Well, we reexamined the perp DNA
得到的罪犯基因
we got from the crime scene
发现我们实际拿到的是罪犯和受害者基因
and discovered that what we actually had was a mixture of samples,
混在一起的样本  这在法庭上是无效的
perp and the victim, which makes it unreliable in court.
孩子们  请回到楼上去
Girls, I need you to go upstairs, please.
星期一  我会举行一个记者招待会
On Monday, I'm holding a press conference
宣布重新开启调查...
to announce the reopening of the investigation...
正式对外宣布撤销
and to officially go on record regarding the dropping
对泰瑞·梅特兰的指控
of charges against Terry Maitland.
你们一家已经受够了折磨
Your family has suffered enough,
我只想尽可能...
and I just want to do whatever I...
因为你在起诉我和我办公室...
Because of your pending lawsuits against me and my office...
我不能向你表达我的心声
I have to refrain from telling you what is in my heart.
我完全理解
I completely understand.
他是来谴责你的吗
Was he mean to you?
不  亲爱的  他不是来谴责我的
No, my love, he wasn't mean to me.
飞机还是开车
Flying or driving?
开车
Driving.
大概要十小时吧  去芝加哥
About ten hours, right? Chicago?
-是的  -十小时吧
- Yeah. - Ten hours?
我在路上还要去几个地方
I have a couple of stops I have to make along the way.
要是以后还有机会
You know, I wouldn't mind teaming up again,
我不介意继续合作
the opportunity ever arose.
最好下次能有一些简单点的活
I mean, preferably on something simple
比如三重黑帮谋杀案之类的
like a gangland triple homicide. Something like that.
我在东雪莉的时候
When I was in the caves,
睡仙问我  我为什么这么容易
El Cuco asked me, uh, why I was so open
接受了它的存在
to believing in its existence.
我的父亲曾经是军人  我小时候
My father was ex-military and when I was little,
他会说  "人才是最了解人的"
he would say, "A man knows a man."
要是我当时在洞穴里有时间思考
Well, if I had the time to think in that cave
并且要好好回答那个问题的话
and the inclination to answer that thing,
我会说
I would have said...
"局外人最了解局外人"
"An outsider knows an outsider."
霍莉  那里还有什么
Holly. What else is out there?
我从来没有告诉你  但是...我看到了德雷克
I never told you but... I saw Derek.
他...和我说话了
He... spoke to me.
-他说了什么  -那...
- What did he say? - Well, it--
那并不是德雷克  所以...
it wasn't Derek, so...
拉夫  告诉他说了什么  让我高兴一下也好
Ralph-- Tell me what he said. Just humor me.
他说我应该放他离开
He said that I need to let him go.
放他离开
Let him go?
想得美
Well, fat chance of that.
我不知道
I don't know.
我倒是觉得这次的经历
I like to think the way this whole experience...
打开了新的世界
cracked the world open.
也许他下一次再出现
Maybe the next time he appears,
就会是真正的德里克了
maybe it's gonna be the real Derek.
或者也许再过几年
Or maybe after a few years pass,
很多年
many more years,
我们就能去看他了
we'll just go visit him.
弗兰基·皮特森
2007年6月23日
2019年3月30日
切诺基市儿童被害案疑犯无罪释放
德文·吉尔菲林将会带来《来一起努力》
"Get Out and Get It". That's Devon Gilfillian.
在他之前  贾尼斯·乔普林将会带来《趁年轻》
Before that, Janis Joplin with "Get It While You Can",
罗伯特·菲力也将在节目开始前
and a song of the same name by Robert Finley
献唱这首歌曲
right before that on the show.
加下来  我将为所有听众
Now, here's an obscure little gem
带来一点休暇时光
for all your audiophiles out there.
这是迪克西兰爵士乐复兴的曲子
This is a Dixieland revival romp,
在1963年登上公告牌热榜第二
peaking at number two on the Billboard Hot 100, 1963,
这是我个人最喜欢的一首歌
and it's one of my personal favorites.
请欣赏
Here it is.